（キバ）あぁ　まだ体痛ぇ。
Oh, my body’s still hurts.
ったく　不用意に地面でなんか
寝るもんじゃねえな。
You can’t sleep on the ground
without the right gear.
（赤丸）ワン！
（サクラ）ごめん　ごめん。
Sorry! I’m sorry!
まあ　いいけどよ。
But I guess it’s okay.
今日中には里に戻れそうだし。
It looks like we can get back to
the village before the day’s over.
（ナルト）ん？　カカシ先生は？
What about Kakashi Sensei?
（サクラ）それなら…。
Yes, about that…
（カカシ）じゃ　頼んだよ。
I’m counting on you.
カカシ先生　あれ…。
Kakashi Sensei, what was that?
各隠れ里に伝令を送った。
Messages to every Hidden Village.
共同戦線を張るんだ。
We are working toward
a united front.
重要情報は
早めに共有しておかないと。
We have to share critical intel
as early as possible.
暁は尾獣を持っている。
The Akatsuki possess
the Tailed Beasts.
これ以上　手をこまねいている
場合ではない。
We cannot go on and do nothing.
それに　ヤツらを率いているのは
あの　うちはマダラ。
Besides, they are led by
that Madara Uchiha.
打てる手は
すべて打っておかねば。
We must do everything we can now.
わかっている。
I know that.
なら　さっさと承認せい。
Then hurry up and
give your approval.
おぬしは
この戦に負けてもいいと申すか？
Are you willing to lose this war?
だが　忍連合軍…
忍に力を持たせすぎて→
But the Allied Shinobi Force…
What if we give them
too much power
後々　厄介なことになったら
どうする？
and this decision comes back
to haunt us later?
おぬしは　そんなに自国の忍が
信用できぬのか？
Do you really distrust
your own nation’s shinobi that much?
まずは…。
First of all…
（天画）あの…　そろそろ
決断していただかないと。
We will need you to come
to a decision soon.
蓄電池がなくなりそうで。
The battery is running low.
It is such a long distance.
なんせ　遠距離なもんで。
オホン！　結論を出そう。
Let’s conclude this.
雷は承認する。
Lightning approves this.
土もだ。　前に同じ。
Earth agrees with Lightning.
風も同じく承認する。
Wind approves this as well.
いいんでないかい。
うん　火も承認。
Why not?
Fire approves it.
わかった。　水も承認。
All right.
Water approves it as well.
（天画）では　これをもって
忍連合軍の結成が承認されました。
So now, with this…
The formation of
the Allied Shinobi Force is ratified.
モニターを録画。
Monitors on record.
I, Tenga, shall serve as the witness.
私　天画が
これらの証人となります。
お疲れさまでございます。
Thank you all very much.
This ends the transmission.
通信　終了いたしました。
ふぅ　やっと終わったえ。
It is finally over.
では　すぐ木ノ葉に
連絡するとよいぞ。
Now it would be good to contact
the Hidden Leaf at once.
The Five Great Nations Mobilize
Sakura…
（いの）サクラ
今頃どのへんにいるのかな？
I wonder where she is now.
ちゃんと
ナルトを説得できたのかしら。
Was she able to persuade Naruto?
（チョウジ）キバや　リーだっているんだ。
きっと大丈夫だよ。
Kiba and Lee are with her.
I’m sure everything’s okay.
Still…
でも…。
（シカマル）まあ　ここで俺らが→
Well, worrying about it here
won’t do any good.
やきもきしても
しかたねえってこった。
ん？
何かあったか？
Did something happen?
Hey, Shikamaru.
（シカク）おい　シカマル。
ちょっといいか。
Can I talk to you?
親父！
Dad?
風影様が帰ってきたぞ！
TOBIMARU
Lord Kazekage has returned.
（テマリ）飛丸の文は受け取ったな？
はい！
Did you receive
Tobimaru’s message?
Yes, ma’am!
（カンクロウ）大名たちから
報告はあったか？
Any word from the Feudal Lords?
Yes, just a while ago.
ええ　つい先ほど。
It said that they all
gave their approval.
全員一致で
無事承認されたそうです。
思ったより早かったな。
It came sooner than expected.
事が事だからな。
Well, considering the situation…
いつもは腰の重い大名たちも
動かざるをねえってわけだ。
Those lords, who often act slowly,
had no choice but to act quickly.
忙しくなるぜ。
Things are gonna get busy.
（我愛羅）すぐに会議を開く。
上役たちに招集をかけろ。
We’ll meet immediately.
Send for all the officials at once.
お帰りなさいませ　水影様。
Welcome home, Lady Mizukage.
We received word from
the Feudal Lord.
先ほど　大名から
報告がありました。
（青）聞こう。　この場で話せ。
Let’s hear it, go ahead!
Sir. The Feudal Lords of
the Five Great Nations
ハッ。　五大国大名は
忍連合軍を承認する　と。
have approved
the Allied Shinobi Forces.
（水影）そうですか。
いよいよですね。
Is that so?
It’s finally time.
We must hurry to get
ourselves ready too.
我々も急ぎ　態勢を整えなければ。
それにしても
敵の手に落ちる前に→
But it’s a good thing we were
able to secure the Eight-Tails
before it fell into
our enemy’s hands.
無事　八尾を確保できたのは
よかったですな。
そのときの戦闘により→
It’s said that the Akatsuki member
Kisame Hoshigaki
暁　構成員の干柿鬼鮫を
倒したとのこと。
was defeated in that fight.
開戦前に　敵の戦力を削ぐことに
成功したのですから→
We were able to weaken the enemy’s
might before the war began,
so that was great.
結構なことです。
さすが雷影様だ。
Just what you’d expect
from Lord Raikage.
《長十郎：干柿鬼鮫…　本当に？
Kisame Hoshigaki…
Really? That guy who was
called the Tailless Tailed Beast.
あの尾のない尾獣と
いわれた人が…》
どうした　長十郎。
いえ　その…　なんでも。
What’s the matter, Chojuro?
No… Umm… Nothing…
元気がないな。
腹でも減っているのか？
Where’s your energy?
Are you hungry, or something?
よし　俺が後で
飯をおごってやろう。
I’ve got it! I’ll treat you to
a meal after this!
Huh?
えっ？
もちろん　メニューはトンカツだ！
Of course, it’ll be fried pork cutlets!
戦に備えた　ゲン担ぎってな。
For good luck in battle!
FRIED PORK CUTLETS
Fried pork cutlets…
HUSBAND HUNTING
Husband hunting?!
I-I don’t care for…oily foods.
僕　油っぽいのは　ちょっと…。
何を情けないことを！
How pitiful!
Keep that up and you’ll fail
at the crucial moment.
そんな調子じゃ
肝心なときに失敗するぞ！
HUSBAND HUNTING
FAIL
HUSBAND HUNTING?!
Husband hunting…
You’ll…fail?!
At times like these,
こういうときは
素直に先輩の言うことを…。
you should accept whatever
your elder tells you.
黙れ　殺すぞ。
Shut up, or I’ll kill you.
えっ！？
（黒ツチ）早いな。　もうかよ。
Well, that was quick.
（赤ツチ）大名たちも
尾獣や　マダラの名前が出たから→
Those lords worked quickly
because the Tailed Beasts
and Madara were mentioned.
決めるのが早かったんだに。
（黒ツチ）尾獣はともかく
マダラっていったら大昔のヤツだろ？
I can understand the Tailed Beasts.
But isn’t Madara someone
from long ago?
相当なジジイなんじゃねえの？
He must be really old by now.
見た感じ
そうは見えなかっただに。
He didn’t look that old.
なぁ　うちのジジイと
どっちがヨイヨイ？
So who looks older,
him or our old man?
I tell you.
The ignorant have it so easy.
（土影）まったく　ものを知らんヤツは
のん気でいいわい。
だって　戦争とか
いまいち実感ないんだよな。
Well, something like war…
It just doesn’t seem real.
先が思いやられるのう。
Heaven help us…
if all our shinobi are young kids
who know nothing of war.
今の忍どもは
大戦を知らぬ　ガキばっかじゃぜ。
Of course, you-know-who got
talked down by one of those kids.
誰かさんは　そのガキに
言い負かされてたけどね。
((アンタたちはいつ　己を捨てた？))
When did you all forsake yourselves?
Well, let’s just see what
the young ones have got!
ま　若いヤツらの
お手並み拝見じゃぜ。
報告によると　ずいぶん荒れた
会談だったようだな。
According to the reports,
it seems there was quite
an uproar at the conference.
六代目火影が
事を有利に運ぼうとしたことも→
It was unusual that the Sixth Hokage
tried to turn things in his favor.
異例の事態だが。
（バキ）開催場所を極秘とし
厳重な警備をしいていた会場が→
The venue was kept secret
and security was tight.
そうも　たやすく
襲撃されるとは考えられん。
Who would have thought that place
would be breeched so easily?
しかし　それこそが暁だ。
But that’s the Akatsuki for you.
They got into the place so easily
and threw us into an uproar.
ヤツらは　いとも簡単に
議場に入り込み→
我々を　かく乱してみせた。
詳しく聞こう。
Tell us everything.
会談の開始直後。
It was right after
the conference started.
They suddenly appeared out
of the least expected place.
もっとも予想だにしない場所から
ヤツらは突然　現れた。
Hello!
((ゼツ：ハロー！
（雷影）次から次へとなんだ！
One problem after another!
Now what?!
暁か。
じゃな。
Is it the Akatsuki?!
It seems so.
うちはサスケが侵入してるよ。
Sasuke Uchiha has snuck in!
Now, where could he be hiding?
さて…
どこに隠れているんでしょうか？
I’m very irritated right now.
（サスケ）俺は今　いらだっている。
If you attack,
I’ll show no mercy.
来るなら
手加減はできそうにない。
それは　こちらとて同じ！
I would say the same to you!
重流暴！
Elbow Bolt!
（ダルイ）嵐遁　励挫鎖苛素！
Gale Style: Laser Circus!
Sasuke!
《香燐：サスケ！》
《香燐：こ　これって…》
W-What is this?!
(我愛羅　お前以上の絶対防御だ))
Gaara… This is even greater
than your Ultimate Defense.
Impossible!
そんな！
風影以上の絶対防御だと？
An absolute defense greater
than that of the Kazekage?
ヤツは　そう言っていた。
That’s what he said.
It must have been a Visual Jutsu
of the Mangekyo Sharingan.
万華鏡写輪丸の
瞳術の一種だろう。
そして　ヤツは…。
And then…
我々をまき　会談場へと向かった。
They made us withdraw
and they headed for
the conference room.
きたか。
He’s coming.
（フー）上か！
Above?
((このまま
いい男が溶けて崩れていくのは→
It pains my heart
every time I see such
a handsome man melt away.
いつ見ても　心が痛むけど。
死んでもらう。
But you have to die.
こんなガキが　デイダラをのう。
So a brat like you
defeated Deidara?
お前に恨みはないが→
Well, I hold no grudge against you,
but many ninja wish you dead.
忍の皆が　死を望んどる。
じゃあのう。
So long…
Particle Style:
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
塵遁　原界剥離の術！
My name is Madara Uchiha.
（マダラ）俺の名は　うちはマダラ。
サスケ！
Sasuke!
（マダラ）お前たちに　ある説明をする。
I have something I want
to explain to you all.
それを　理解してもらった上で
聞きたいことがある。
And once you comprehend it,
I want to pose a question.
To think that four Kage together
couldn’t take on Sasuke Uchiha.
影たちが　４人がかりで
うちはサスケ１人しとめきれぬとは。
これが　暁の力。
That is the power of the Akatsuki.
Why did they attack
the Five Kage Summit?
ヤツらは　なぜ
五影会談を襲撃してきた？
To show off their strength?
自分たちの力を
見せつけるためか？
それぞれの行動を見るかぎり→
Judging from their individual actions,
it is difficult to say whether
the objectives of
うちはサスケと　マダラの目的が
一致しているかは定かではない。
Sasuke Uchiha and Madara
were the same.
しかし　マダラのほうは
自らの計画を有利に進めるため→
However, it seems that
Madara thought, with any luck,
he could take
the five Kage hostage
あわよくば　五影を
人質にとろうと考えていたようだ。
in order to advance his own plan.
五影を！？　なんと不遜な！
The five Kage?! How arrogant!
そのマダラの計画とは？
What was Madara’s plan?
ヤツは　月の眼計画と呼んでいた。
He called it his
"Project Tsuki no Me."
俺の一尾をはじめ→
He already has possession
of seven Tailed Beasts,
七尾までの尾獣が
すでに　ヤツの手の中にある。
beginning with my One-Tail.
マダラは　残り２体の尾獣を集め→
It seems Madara plans to collect
the two remaining Tailed Beasts
and resurrect the Ten-Tails,
尾獣の集合体である
十尾を復活させ→
the combination of every Tailed Beast,
自らを
十尾の人柱力にするつもりらしい。
in order to make himself
the Jinchuriki of the Ten-Tails.
そして　その力を持って
世界を無限月読にかけ→
And using that power,
he would place the world
under Infinite Tsukuyomi.
すべての人間を支配下に置き
コントロールする。
And he would place
all humans under his rule,
and he would control them.
わだかまりも　争いもない世界。
ヤツは　そう言ってたがな。
A world free of antagonism and strife.
Is that what he said?
Ridiculous! That would be
the end of the world.
バカな！
そんなものは世界の終焉だ！
そのとおりだ！
Exactly. That’s all the more reason
we must stop him.
だからこそ
全力で阻止せねばならない。
そのための忍連合軍だ。
That is what the Allied
Shinobi Forces are for.
しかし　そうなると　志村ダンゾウの
行方が気になりますな…。
But if that is the case,
I worry about the whereabouts
of Danzo Shimura.
ヤツは長い間　木ノ葉を
陰で牛耳っていた男だと聞きます。
I hear that he was
the one controlling the Hidden Leaf
from behind the scenes
for a long time.
我々が　一枚岩に
なろうとしているときに→
I’d hate to get shot in
the back at a time
when we are all trying
to build solidarity.
後ろから撃たれでもしたら
たまりませんからな。
その件については→
As to that,
every Hidden Village should
now be out searching for him.
現在　各里が
行方を追っているはずだ。
一度　水影の配下が
接触したらしいが…。
It seems some of
the Mizukage’s followers
did come in contact
with him once, but…
なにごとだ？　会議中だぞ。
What? We’re in the middle
of a meeting.
恐れ入ります。
緊急の報告です。
Pardon me.
There is an urgent report.
入れ。
Come in.
We have received a message
木ノ葉の　はたけカカシより
伝令がありました。
from Kakashi Hatake
of the Hidden Leaf.
はたけカカシ以下　２名の忍が→
It seems Kakashi Hatake
and two other ninja
came upon Sasuke Uchiha
and Madara, and fighting ensued.
うちはサスケ　マダラと接触
および　交戦。
志村ダンゾウの死を
確認したそうです。
It seems they were able to
confirm the death of Danzo Shimura.
ダンゾウが死んだ！？
なんと！
Danzo is dead?!
What?!
一度は　火影となったほどの
実力者が？
Someone so skilled that
he became the Hokage?
What about Madara and Sasuke?
マダラとサスケは？
ハッ！
Sir! It seems they used
the Transportation Technique to disappear.
時空間忍術で
行方をくらましたもようです。
確かに暁は強い。
It’s certain, the Akatsuki
is definitely strong.
Their capability of war waging
is unknown.
その戦力は未知数だ。
しかし　史上初となる→
But the true strength of
our Allied Shinobi Forces,
我々　忍連合軍の実力も
また未知数。
which is unparalleled in history,
is also unknown.
Earth, Water, Fire, Wind,
and Lightning…
土　水　火　風　雷。
If we unite all the shinobi’s power,
すべての忍の力を結集すれば→
I believe we can
counter them thoroughly.
俺は十分　対抗できると考える。
何より　この戦いに勝たねば
世界は終わる。
Above all, we must win this battle
or the world will end.
今すぐ　忍具と食料の備蓄を
開始しろ。
Begin stockpiling ninja tools
and rations immediately.
戦いに備え　すべての任務は
一時　凍結。
All official missions will
be temporarily halted
in preparation for battle.
Give me a list of all shinobi
belonging to the village.
里に所属する
すべての忍のリストを提出し→
At the same time,
同時に　各部隊ごとに
戦術プランの検討に入れ。
I want each platoon to begin
preparing their tactical plans.
No way! Sasuke attacked
the Five Kage Summit?!
そんな！　サスケ君が
五影会談を襲撃したなんて！
じき　正式に発表されるそうだ。
I hear they’re about to announce it.
今　上のヤツらは
てんやわんやらしい。
Seems there is utter confusion
among the officials.
ホントにサスケは
木ノ葉を潰した暁の一員なんだね。
So it’s true that Sasuke is
a member of the Akatsuki,
who crushed the Hidden Leaf.
面倒くせぇことになりそうだぜ。
Looks like this is gonna
turn out to be a drag.
水影様のご指示だ。
These are orders
from Lady Mizukage.
至急　忍具の在庫を確認。
Confirm our supplies of
ninja tools immediately!
不足分のリストを作成しろ！
Make a list of anything
we’re short on!
忍連合だか何だか知らないが→
I don’t know about
this Allied Shinobi Forces,
岩のヤツらと組むなんて
ごめんだぜ。
but I won’t join up with
those guys from the Stone.
ああ。　暁は四代目水影の悪夢を
この国に招いた→
The Akatsuki is a hateful group
that brought
the nightmare of
the Fourth Mizukage upon this nation.
憎むべき連中だ。
岩隠れは今まで　さんざん→
The Hidden Stone have used
the Akatsuki again and again,
until now.
暁のヤツらを
利用してきたじゃないか。
いくら上の決定でも→
The higher-ups may order it,
こんなこと
ガンリュウさんが許すわけない。
but there’s no way Ganryu
would accept it.
念入りだな。
You’re being very careful with them.
伝説の傀儡使いの残した
最高傑作だ。
They are the great masterpieces
of a legendary puppeteer.
歴代の操演者たちに→
I cannot allow myself
to be bested
引けを取るわけには
いかねえからよ。
by the generations of
puppeteers before me.
そっちは？
What about you?
現在　遠方任務についている
忍たちに伝令を送ったところだ。
I just sent off messages
to those ninja currently
on far away missions.
しかし　ついに火影殺しとはな。
But to think it has come to
killing a Hokage.
うちはサスケのことか。
You mean Sasuke Uchiha?
わかってはいたが
堕ちるところまで堕ちやがったな。
I knew it, but he’s really fallen
as low as you can get.
だが…。
But…
((ナルト　お前は俺に→
Naruto, you told me,
"I am going to be the Hokage."
自分は火影になる男だと言ったな。
俺は風影になった。
I became the Kazekage.
影の名を背負う覚悟を
決めたなら→
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
then do what is right
as Sasuke's friend.
(サスケの友として　お前が本当に
やるべきことをやれ))
アイツは納得してねえみてえ
だったじゃん。
He didn’t seem to
be convinced, did he?
あきらめないヤツだからな。
It’s because he never gives up.
私たちでさえ近づけなかった
昔の我愛羅を変えた男だ。
He’s the one who changed
the old Gaara,
the one we could never approach.
相手が　どんな闇の中にいようと
最後まで手を差しのべる。
No matter how lost in
the darkness a person might be,
he will hold out his hand.
救おうとする。
He will try to save him.
そういうヤツだ。
我愛羅…。
That’s how he is.
Gaara…
しかし　闇を望んでいるのは
サスケ自身だ。
But it’s Sasuke himself
who’s seeking the darkness.
今回ばかりは。
This time, I don’t think…
It has to be Naruto’s decision
after that.
その先は　ナルトの決断だ。
友として　何をするのか。
What he will do as a friend.
俺はただ　俺のすべてをかけて→
I will simply give my all to
protect my friends…
俺の友と　世界を守る。
and the world!
（木ノ葉丸）あれ？
また　トンビが飛んでるぞ　これ。
Look. There’s another black Kite flying in.
いったい何羽目だ？
How many does that make?
（モエギ）もう　木ノ葉丸ちゃん
そんなこと　どうでもいいでしょ。
Come on, Konohamaru,
forget about that!
それより　どこ行っちゃったのよ
ナルト兄ちゃんは。
I’d rather know where
Naruto has gone!
せっかくの
木ノ葉の英雄新聞なのに。
It’s a Leaf Hero Newspaper,
after all.
肝心のインタビューが
埋まらないじゃない。
I haven’t snagged
the all-important interview!
ん～　俺とエロ忍術勝負したときは→
Yeah. When he and I had
that Pervy Ninjutsu contest,
すぐ帰ってくるようなこと
言ってたけど。
he said he would come right back.
Wha—?!
何よ　エロ忍術って！
What do you mean
by Pervy Ninjutsu?!
木ノ葉丸ちゃん　不潔！
You’re so lewd, Konohamaru!
不潔って…
俺の必殺技だぞ　これ！
Lewd?! You’re talking about
my secret lethal move!
（ウドン）木ノ葉丸君！
ナルトの兄ちゃん帰ってきたって。
Konohamaru! They say Naruto
has come home!
サクラ…。
Sakura…
（サクラ）ただいま。
I’m back.
親父から聞いたぜ。　サスケのヤツが…。
I heard from my dad…
about Sasuke.
ああ。
Yeah…
それに
アイツとは直接　やりあってきた。
And I fought with him.
やりあったって　お前…。
"Fought"? You mean with Sasuke?!
サスケとか？
あとで詳しく話す。
I’ll give you the details later.
悪いけど
みんなを集めといてくんねえか？
Sorry, but would you mind getting
everybody together?
言っておきてえこともあるしな。
There’s something I want to say.
わかった。
Okay.
ナルト兄ちゃん！　待ってたぞ　これ。
Naruto.
We were waiting for yo
おう　お前ら。
あとは
兄ちゃんのインタビューが取れれば→
英雄新聞が完成するんだ。
ナルト兄ちゃん　取材　取材！
ああ　そういや　そうだったな。
でも　報告があるから　また今度な。
（モエギ）え～！
また今度って　そんな！
（ウドン）約束したのに！
もう　じらすんだから！
ナルト兄ちゃんのいけず！
ねぇねぇ　今度っていつ？
そうよ！
私たち　ずっと待ってたのよ！
ねぇ　ナルト兄ちゃん！
ちょっと　木ノ葉丸ちゃんも
なんとか言ったら？
何か　あったのかな？
え？
ナルト兄ちゃん
ちょっと雰囲気　変わったような。
はぁ？
何言ってるの　木ノ葉丸ちゃん。
どう見ても　いつもどおりの
ナルト兄ちゃんじゃない。
そうなんだけど…。
（ウドン）ねぇ！　いつなの？
（くもじい）
もしもし　そこのあなた。
たまには
空から日本を眺めてみる→
というのは　どうじゃろう？
今回は　東京の離島　伊豆諸島と→
東京の人混み行列地帯の→
豪華２本立てスペシャルじゃ。
（くもみ）すごい！
伊豆諸島では　離島ならではの
お仕事を　次々と発見。